Association of University Evening Colleges (AUEC) Records
Association of University Evening Colleges (AUEC) Records
- AUEC files
  - Membership
    - Institutions
      - Norfolk College of William and Mary, See Membership: Personal: McClelland, Dr. Robert C.
      - Northeastern University (Albert E. Everett, Dean), 1956-1962 (Box 17)
        See also Membership: Personal: Abercrombie, Gurth I.; Allen, Lawrence A.; Thompson, Clarence H.
      - Northern Illinois University (Virgil Alexander, Director), 1957 (Box 17)
      - Northwestern University (Daniel R. Lang, Dean), 1956-1962; 2 folders (Box 17)
        See also Membership: Personal: Luck, Dr. Martha S.; Shanafield, Harold A.
      - Ohio State University (Luke K. Cooperrider, Director), 1959 (Box 18)
      - Oregon State System of Higher Education (James C. Caughlan, Director), 1957-1962 (Box 18)
      - Pace College (Edward J. Mortola, Vice President), 1958-1959 (Box 18)
      - Pennsylvania Military College (Dean B. Arnold, Associate Dean), 1959 (Box 18)
      - Pennsylvania State University (E.L. Keller, Director of General Education), 1956-1961 (Box 18)
      - Polytechnic Institute of Brooklyn (Charles E. Schnaffer, Dean), 1958 (Box 18)
        See also Membership: Personal: Heckhaus, Philip L., III
      - Portland Extension Center, See Membership: Personal: Caughlan, James C.
      - C. W. Post College (Frederick O. Bissell, Director), 1962 (Box 18)
      - Poughkeepsie Center of Syracuse University (Robert S. McDowell), 1957 (Box 18)
      - Pratt Institute (Israel Sweet, Dean; Bernard Reed, Dean), 1958-1961 (Box 18)
        See also Membership: Personal: Shanken, Edward D.; Sweet, Israel
      - Providence College (Richard D. Danilowicz O.P., Director; William R. Clark O.P., Director), 1956-1957 (Box 18)
      - Purdue University (C.H. Lawshe, Dean; William A. Jones, Calumet Center ), 1960 (Box 18)
        See also Membership: Personal: Elliott, Carl H.; Hunsaker, Herbert C.
      - Queens College (N.Y.) (Glenn Howard, Director), 1957-1962 (Box 18)
      - Queens College (N.C.) (Robert W. Shaw, Director), 1957-1962 (Box 18)
      - Rider College (Sherman V.N. Kent, Dean), 1961-1962 (Box 18)
      - Rochester Institute of Technology (Burton E. Stratton, Director; Robert D. Pease, Dean), 1958-1961 (Box 18)
      - Rockford Evening College (Curtis H. Moore, Dean), 1960-1962 (Box 18)
      - Rockhurst College (Charles P. Cahill S.J., Director), 1957 (Box 18)
      - Roosevelt University (Arthur Hillman, Dean), 1956-1958 (Box 18)
      - Row, Peterson & Co., See Membership: Personal: Posey, Dr. Rollin B.
      - Russell Sage College (George J. Spears, Director), 1956-1962 (Box 18)
      - Rutgers, The State University (John L. Swink, Ernest E. McMahon), 1956-1962 (Box 18)
        See also Membership: Personal: Ekstrom, Dr. J. Fredrik
      - St. John's University (P. Austin Derrig C.M., Associate, Dean), 1959 (Box 18)
      - St. Joseph's College - Calumet (Rev. Edward A. Maziars, Academic Dean), 1957-1959 (Box 18)
      - Seton Hall University (Edward J. Fleming, Dean; John E. O'Brien, Dean), 1957-1960 (Box 18)
      - Shaker Heights City School District, See Membership: Personal: Emery, Dr. Donald G.
      - Sir George Williams College (Robert C. Rae, Dean), 1956-1962 (Box 18)
        See also Membership: Personal: Peets, Dr. Donald L.
      - Southern Illinois University, See Membership: Personal: Seymour, Virgil L.
      - Southern Methodist University (John M. Claunch, Dean), 1957-1962 (Box 18)
      - Spring Hill College (John T. Walsh S.J., Director), 1958-1962 (Box 18)
      - Suffolk University (Joseph H. Strain, Assistant Dean), 1959-1960 (Box 18)
      - Syracuse University (Alexander Charters, Dean), 1956-1962 (Box 18)
        See also Membership: Personal: Ingham, Roy J.; Winters, Clifford L.
      - Texas Christian University (Cortell K. Holsapple), 1957-1962 (Box 18)
      - Thomas More Institute for Adult Education (R. Eric O'Connor S.J., Dean), 1956-1959 (Box 18)
      - Trinity University (Walter P. West, Director), 1957-1958 (Box 19)
      - Tulane University (John P. Dyer, Dean), 1956-1962 (Box 19)
      - University of Akron (D.J. Guzzetta, Dean; W.A. Rogers, Dean), 1958-1962 (Box 19)
        See also Membership: Personal: Matthews, Richard D.
      - University of Bridgeport (James W. Southouse, Director), 1956-1960 (Box 19)
      - University of British Columbia (J.K. Friesen, Director), 1959-1962 (Box 19)
      - University of Buffalo (Robert F. Berner), 1956-1962 (Box 19)
        See also Membership: Personal: Kish, Dr. Nicholas
      - University of California (Paul Sheats, Director), 1956-1962 (Box 19)
      - University of Chattanooga (Charles W. Whitworth, Dean), 1957-1962 (Box 19)
      - University of Chicago (John T. Wilson, Director), 1958-1962 (Box 19)
      - University of Cincinnati (Frank R. Neuffer, Dean), 1959-1960 (Box 19)
        See also Membership: Personal: Settle, Dr. Kenneth B.
      - University of Dayton (Robert E. Donovan, Director), 1956-1962 (Box 19)
      - University of Delaware (Gordon C. Godbey, Director), 1957-1961 (Box 19)
      - University of Denver (Alfred C. Nelson, Dean; W.M. Lewis, Program Coordinator), 1956-1962 (Box 19)
      - University of Detroit (William B. O'Regan, Dean), 1959-1961 (Box 19)
        See also Membership: Personal: Emmet, Dr. Thomas
      - University of Hartford (Ernest A. Dudley, Director), 1956-1962 (Box 19)
      - University of Kansas (N. Webster Rickhoff, Manager), 1957 (Box 20)
      - University of Kansas City (C.J. Stevens, Director), 1957-1962 (Box 20)
        See also Membership: Personal: Kolker, Dr. Berndt L.
      - University of Louisville (William C. Huffman, Dean), 1956-1962 (Box 20)
      - University of Manitoba (A.S.R. Tweedie, Director), 1957-1963 (Box 20)
      - University of Maryland (G. Allen Sager, Assistant Dean), 1956-1961 (Box 20)
        See also Membership: Personal: Quimper, James R.
      - University of Miami (Dan Steinhoff, Dean), 1956-1962 (Box 20)
      - University of Minnesota (Eleanor Salisbury, NUEA Secretary; Julius Nolte, Dean), 1956-1961 (Box 20)
        See also Membership: Personal: Miller, Huntington
      - University of Nebraska (Knute O. Broady, Director), 1958-1962 (Box 20)
      - University of Oklahoma (Howell McGee, Director), 1958-1962 (Box 20)
        See also Membership: Personal: McGee, Howell W.
      - University of Omaha (Donald Emery; Donald Woods, Dean), 1956-1962 (Box 20)
        See also Membership: Personal: Beilis, Dr. Michel
      - University of Pittsburgh (Viers Adams, Dean), 1956-1962 (Box 20)
      - University of Rhode Island (John K. Hackett, Director), 1958-1959 (Box 20)
      - University of Richmond (Melvin L. Greenhut, Associate Dean), 1962 (Box 20)
      - University of Rochester (Howard P. Anderson, Dean), 1957 (Box 20)
      - University of San Francisco (Gerald A. Sugrue S.J., Director), 1958-1960 (Box 20)
        See also Membership: Personal: Beaver, Dr. William A.
      - University of Scranton (Joseph A. Barrett, Director), 1956-1962 (Box 20)
      - University of Southern California (Carl Hancey, Dean), 1956-1960 (Box 20)
      - University of Southern Illinois (Robert W. Duncan, Supervisor), 1958 (Box 20)
      - University of Tampa (James W. Covington), 1961-1962 (Box 20)
        See also Membership: Personal: Speronis, Stephen L.
      - University of Tennessee (James E. Arnold, Dean), 1958 (Box 20)
      - University of Toledo (Ralph C. Kendall, Dean), 1957-1962 (Box 20)
        See also Membership: Personal: Matthews, Richard D.; Setterbo, Dr. Donald B.; Spencer, Dr. Richard A.
      - University of Toronto (D.C. Williams, Director), 1960-1961 (Box 20)
      - University of Tulsa (H. Rodman Jones, Director; Andrew L. Springfield, Director), 1957-1960 (Box 20)
      - University of Washington (M.E. Marts, Director), 1956-1961 (Box 20)
      - University of Wichita (T. Reese Marsh, Director), 1956-1960 (Box 20)
      - University of Wisconsin (Roger W. Axford, Director), 1956-1962 (Box 20)
      - Utica College of Syracuse University (Thomas J. Desmond, Director), 1957-1962 (Box 21)
      - Villa Madonna College (Thomas H. Hanna, Director), 1960-1961 (Box 21)
      - Villanova University (George P. Lawless, Eugene P. Powers), 1956-1960
      - Virginia State College (H.D. Carpenter Jr., Director), 1956 (Box 21)
        See also Membership: Personal: Brown, Dr. George W.C.
      - Washburn University (James M. Young, Director), 1956-1958 (Box 21)
      - Washington University (Willis H. Reals, Ernest Brandenburg), 1956-1961 (Box 21)
        See also Membership: Personal: Spohrer, Dr. Myron A.
      - Wayne State University (Charles L. Jackson), 1959-1961 (Box 21)
      - Western Reserve University (Johns Diekhoff, Dean), 1956-1960 (Box 21)
        See also Membership: Personal: Brown, Dr. Leslie E.
      - Xavier University (Richard T. Deters S.J., Henry J. Wirtenberger), 1957-1961 (Box 21)
        See also Membership: Personal: Walker, Dr. Russ
    - Personal
      - Abercrombie, Gurth I. (Northeastern University), 1959-1961 (Box 21)
      - Allen, Lawrence A. (Northeastern University), 1962 (Box 21)
      - Beaver, Dr. William A. (University of San Francisco), 1961 (Box 21)
      - Beilis, Dr. Michel (University of Omaha), 1962-1964 (Box 21)
      - Benfield, Dr. Howard (Drexel Institute of Technology), 1957-1960 (Box 21)
      - Betz, Dr. Paul R. (St. Joseph's College), 1961-1962 (Box 21)
      - Brown, Dr. George W.C. (Virginia State College), 1962-1964 (Box 21)
      - Brown, Dr. Leslie E. (Western Reserve University), 1956-1957 (Box 21)
      - Caughlan, James C. (Portland Extension Center), 1960-1961 (Box 21)
      - Collins, Dr. Donald E. (Adelphi College, Oakdale), 1962 (Box 21)
      - Cooper, Howard E. (Johns Hopkins University), 1956-1959 (Box 21)
      - Crimi, James E. (Aurora College), 1962 (Box 21)
      - Daigneault, George H. (CSLEA), 1960-1962 (Box 21)
      - Donohue, Dr. John P. (Loyola University), 1961 (Box 21)
      - Egginton, Mary T. (Adelphi University), 1962 (Box 21)
      - Ekstrom, Dr. J. Fredrik (Rutgers University), 1961-1962 (Box 21)
      - Elliott, Carl H. (Purdue University), 1962 (Box 21)
      - Emery, Dr. Donald G. (Shaker Heights City School District ), 1956-1964 (Box 21)
      - Emmet, Dr. Thomas (University of Detroit), 1962 (Box 21)
      - Farmer, Dr. Martha L. (City College of New York ), 1962 (Box 21)
      - Fries, Robert F. (De Paul University), 1960 (Box 21)
      - Fuller, Melvin (Richmond Professional Institute, College of William and Mary ), 1961 (Box 21)
      - Gregg, John F. (Baldwin-Wallace College), 1961 (Box 21)
      - Gwiazda, Dr. Stanley J. (Drexel Institute of Technology), 1961 (Box 21)
      - Heckhaus, Philip L., III (Polytechnic Institute of Brooklyn), 1962 (Box 21)
      - Howard, Dr. Glenn W. (Queens College), 1962 (Box 21)
      - Hunsaker, Herbert C. (Purdue University), 1959-1964 (Box 21)
      - Hunt, Dr. Arch W. (Baylor University), 1962 (Box 21)
      - Ingham, Roy J. (Syracuse University), 1959-1962 (Box 21)
      - Jacobson, Sol (Brooklyn College), 1960-1962 (Box 21)
      - Kish, Dr. Nicholas (University of Buffalo), 1961-1962 (Box 21)
      - Kolker, Dr. Berndt L. (University of Kansas City), 1962 (Box 21)
      - Layton, William P. (National Association of Credit Management), 1958-1963 (Box 21)
      - Luck, Dr. Martha S. (Northwestern University), 1961 (Box 21)
      - McClelland, Dr. Robert C. (Norfolk College of William and Mary), 1961 (Box 21)
      - McGee, Howell W. (University of Oklahoma ), 1960-1962 (Box 21)
      - Matthews, Richard D. (University of Toledo, University of Akron), 1957-1961 (Box 21)
      - Meyer, Dr. Peter (Queens College), 1961 (Box 21)
      - Miller, Huntington (University of Minnesota), 1960-1963 (Box 21)
      - Montgomery, George (Drexel Institute of Technology), 1959 (Box 21)
      - O'Neill, Rev. Charles A., S.J. (Fordham University), 1961 (Box 21)
      - Peets, Dr. Donald L. (Sir George Williams University), 1961 (Box 21)
      - Posey, Dr. Rollin B. (Row, Peterson & Co.), 1960 (Box 21)
      - Power, Franklin A. (Boston University), 1962 (Box 21)
      - Powers, Eugene P. (East Stroudsburg Teachers College ), 1960 (Box 21)
      - Quimper, James R. (University of Maryland ), 1961-1962 (Box 21)
      - Setterbo, Dr. Donald B. (University of Toledo ), 1961 (Box 21)
      - Settle, Dr. Kenneth B. (University of Cincinnati ), 1961 (Box 21)
      - Seymour, Virgil L. (Southern Illinois University ), 1960 (Box 21)
      - Shanafield, Harold A. (Northwestern University ), 1962 (Box 21)
      - Shanken, Edward D. (Pratt Institute), 1963 (Box 21)
      - Spencer, Dr. Richard A. (University of Toledo ), 1961 (Box 21)
      - Speronis, Stephen L. (University of Tampa ), 1962-1964 (Box 21)
      - Spingarn, Edward (Brooklyn College), 1962 (Box 21)
      - Spohrer, Dr. Myron A. (Washington University), 1961 (Box 21)
      - Stephans, Clarence H. (Newark College of Engineering ), 1958 (Box 21)
      - Stern, Bernard H. (Brooklyn College), 1957 (Box 21)
      - Sweet, Israel (Pratt Institute), 1961 (Box 21)
      - Thompson, Clarence H. (Northeastern University), 1961-1964 (Box 21)
      - Walker, Dr. Russ (Xavier University), 1961 (Box 21)
      - Winters, Clifford L. (Syracuse University), 1957-1962 (Box 21)
    - Rosters, 1946-1959 (Box 21)
  - Miscellaneous, 1955-1958 (Box 22)
  - Newsletter
    - Correspondence, 1952-1963 (Box 22)
    - Costs, 1959-1960 (Box 22)
    - Forms and mechanics, 1959 (Box 22)
    - "From the Dean's Desk", 1962 (Box 22)
    - "Introducing New Members", 1962 (Box 22)
    - Newsletter
      - 1940-1960, 4 folders (Box 22)
      - 1961-1967, 3 folders (Box 23)
  - Officers, lists, 1962 (Box 23)
  - Personnel, 1954-1964; 7 folders (Box 23)
  - Policies and procedures, 1950-1960 (Box 24)
  - Purposes and Objectives, 1958-1960 (Box 24)
  - Regions
    - Regional groups, 1955-1963 (Box 24)
    - Regional meetings, 1951-1961 (Box 24)
    - Regional meetings
      - Cincinnati, 1955 (Box 24)
      - Louisville, 1956 (Box 24)
      - Evansville, Indiana, 1957 (Box 24)
    - Regional reports, 1968-1969 (Box 24)
  - Studies
    - Administrative policies, 1947-1952 (Box 24)
    - Business programs, 1945-1952 (Box 24)
    - Extracurricular activities, 1959-1960 (Box 24)
    - Other research, 1952-1963 (Box 25)
  - "Who's Who in the AUEC", 1951 (Box 25)
- Subject files on adult education organizations
  - Adult Education Association
    - AEA-AUEC relationship, 1959 (Box 25)
    - Council of National Organizations for Adult Education
      - AUEC Membership in CNO, 1957-1961 (Box 25)
      - Correspondence, 1954-1961 (Box 25)
  - American Council on Education
    - AUEC Membership, 1951-1959 (Box 25)
    - Correspondence, 1959-1962 (Box 25)
  - Canadian Adult Education Association, 1962-1963; rosters (Box 25)
  - Center for the Study of Liberal Education for Adults
    - AUEC-CSLEA Activities, 1951-1960 (Box 25)
    - Leadership Conference, 1953 (Box 25)
    - Leadership Conference, 1954 (Box 25)
    - Leadership Conference, 1955; 2 folders (Box 25, 26)
    - Leadership Conference, 1956; 2 folders (Box 26)
    - Leadership Conference, 1957 (Box 26)
    - Leadership Conference, 1958 (Box 26)
    - Leadership Conference, 1959 (Box 26)
    - Leadership Conference, 1960 (Box 26)
    - Leadership Conference, 1961 (Box 26)
    - Leadership Conference, 1962 (Box 26)
    - Leadership Conference, 1963 (Box 27)
    - Leadership Conference, 1964 (Box 27)
  - Education-Business Foundation, 1950-1956 (Box 27)
  - Evening colleges
    - Deans, undated (Box 27)
    - Influences, 1953 (Box 27)
    - Problems, undated (Box 27)
    - Terms, undated (Box 27)
  - National University Extension Association (NUEA)
    - AUEC-NUEA Statistical Report, 1960-1961 (Box 27)
    - AUEC-NUEA Statistical Report, 1962-1963 (Box 27)
    - AUEC-NUEA Statistical Report, 1963-1964
      - A-G, 3 folders (Box 27)
      - H-Z, University of A-University of L, 9 folders (Box 28)
      - University of M-University of Z, 4 folders (Box 29)
    - AUEC-NUEA Statistical Report, 1964-1965
      - A-H, 4 folders (Box 29)
      - I-Z, University of A-University of B, 11 folders (Box 30)
      - University of C-University of Z, 7 folders (Box 31)
    - AUEC-NUEA Statistical Report, 1966-1967
      - A-M, 4 folders (Box 31)
      - N-Z, University of A-University of Z, 6 folders (Box 32)
    - AUEC-NUEA Statistical Report, 1967-1968
      - A-I, 3 folders (Box 32)
      - J-Z, University of A-University of S, 7 folders (Box 33)
      - University of T-University of Z (Box 34)
    - AUEC-NUEA Statistical Report, Correspondence, 1957-1968 (Box 34)
    - Committee on Liberal Education, 1957-1958 (Box 34)
    - Correspondence, 1950 (Box 34)
    - Joint Committee, 1955-1965 (Box 34)
    - Joint Uniform Reporting Committee, 1959-1963 (Box 34)
    - Meetings
      - Gatlinburg, Tenn., 1954 (Box 34)
      - New England, Joint Conference, 1960 (Box 34)
    - Study Advisory Committee, 1957 (Box 34)
  - Other
    - AUEC relationship to other adult education groups, 1964 (Box 34)
    - AUEC representation at other adult education meetings, 1957-1963 (Box 34)